Class of 1895 Records, 1891-1960
Smith College Archives
Class of 1895 Records
1891-1960
Smith College. Class of 1895.
RG 80
25 boxes (14.33 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
This collection is in 25 boxes and contains photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, and other memorabilia from the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1895, as well as individual student files.
Historical Note
The Class of 1895 was the seventeenth entering class and the seventeenth graduating class of Smith College.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Class of 1895 records, 1891-1960, contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1895, including materials from commencement, reunions, senior dramatics, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, and other memorabilia.
Individual biographical files are also available, and often include photographs, photo albums, newspaper clippings, letters and correspondences, and class notes.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The Class of 1895 records were created by the students and alumnae of the Class and donated to the College Archives.
- Baccalaureate 1895 (Box 1496, Folder 1)
- Basketball Team 1893 (Box 1496, Folder 2)
- Commencement 1895 (Box 1496, Folder 3)
- Commencement Music 1895 (Box 1496, Folder 4)
- Commencement Photographs 1895 (Box 1496, Folder 5)
- Commencement Speaker 1895 (Box 1496, Folder 6)
- Class Dramatics 1895 (Box 1496, Folder 7)
- Groups 1891-1895 (Box 1496, Folder 8)
- Groups 1891-1895 (Box 1496, Folder 9)
- History 1891-1895 (Box 1496, Folder 10)
- Ivy Day 1895 (Box 1496, Folder 11)
- Ivy Day Photographs 1895 (Box 1496, Folder 12)
- Junior Prom 1894 (Box 1496, Folder 13)
- Junior Prom 1894 (Box 1496, Folder 14)
- Junior Reception 1894 (Box 1496, Folder 15)
- Junior Ushers 1894 (Box 1496, Folder 16)
- Class Letters 1953-1962 (Box 1496, Folder 17)
- Organizations 1895 (Box 1496, Folder 18)
- Songs 1893-1895 (Box 1497, Folder 1)
- Seat 1962 (Box 1497, Folder 2)
- Senior Drama 1895 (Box 1497, Folder 3)
- Senior Party at Morris House 1895 (Box 1497, Folder 4)
- Sophomore Reception 1894 (Box 1497, Folder 5)
- Class Supper 1895 (Box 1497, Folder 6)
- Student Rooms 1895 (Box 1497, Folder 7)
- Reunions 1896 (Box 1498, Folder 1)
- Reunions 1900 (Box 1498, Folder 2)
- Reunions 1905 (Box 1498, Folder 3)
- Reunions 1915 (Box 1498, Folder 4)
- Reunions 1920 (Box 1498, Folder 5)
- Reunions 1925 (Box 1498, Folder 6)
- Reunions 1935 (Box 1498, Folder 7)
- Reunions 1940 (Box 1498, Folder 8)
- Reunions 1945 (Box 1498, Folder 9)
- Reunions 1950 (Box 1498, Folder 10)
- Reunions 1951 (Box 1498, Folder 11)
- Reunions 1952 (Box 1498, Folder 12)
- Reunions 1955 (Box 1498, Folder 13)
- Reunions 1960 (Box 1498, Folder 14)
- Reunions n.d. (Box 1498, Folder 15)
- Reunion Photographs 1896-1960 (Box 1498, Folder 16)
- Reunion Songs n.d. (Box 1498, Folder 17)
- Senior Dramatics 1895 (Box 1499, Folder 1)
- Senior Dramatics 1897 (Box 1499, Folder 2)
- Senior Dramatics 1897 (Box 1499, Folder 3)
- Senior Dramatics Photographs 1895 (Box 1499, Folder 4)
- Senior Dramatics Photographs 1895 (Box 1499, Folder 5)
- Senior Dramatics Photographs 1895 (Box 1499, Folder 6)
- Senior Dramatics Photographs 1895 (Box 1499, Folder 7)